{
    "id": "eab2e1c8b6284932bb926a46c8da342f",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I had the required qualifications but I ………………………………… get the job anyhow.",
            "description": "When the verb in one coordinate clause is in the past tense, the verb in the other coordinate clause is also likely to be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "don't",
                "didn't",
                "hadn't"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The higher we climbed, the colder we …………………………….",
            "description": "The same tense is used in both clauses in this construction. ",
            "answers": [
                "feels",
                "felt",
                "had felt"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She has never …………………………….. to anybody.",
            "description": "Use the past participle after has/have/had.",
            "answers": [
                "apologize",
                "apologized",
                "apologizes"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. to wait.",
            "description": "The passive verb is required here because the subject is not the doer of the action. ",
            "answers": [
                "told",
                "have told",
                "was told"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Playing computer games for hours on end ……………………………. not a good idea.",
            "description": "Here the subject is the ing form playing ing forms are treated as singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "is"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. fast, I was able to catch up with him.",
            "description": "When both clauses have the same subject, it is sometimes possible to connect them with a present participle. ",
            "answers": [
                "Run",
                "Having run",
                "Running"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Nobody knows what ……………………………… to him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "happens",
                "happened",
                "had happened"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They disqualified her for ……………………………….. late to the finals.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "being",
                "been",
                "having being"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Plato’s philosophy ……………………………. throughout the world.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "has disseminated",
                "has been disseminated",
                "had disseminated"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He was a dissolute young man who ………………………………….. only of his own pleasure.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "thinks",
                "thought",
                "thinking"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If enough members ………………………., the new bill won’t be approved.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "dissents",
                "dissented",
                "dissent"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "His complete disregard of others ……………………………. him the respect of his friends.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "loses",
                "lost",
                "had lost"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}